（ナレーション）＜西暦２１９９年＞
＜人類は
ガミラスとの戦いに敗れ→
滅びゆこうとしていた＞
＜人類滅亡まで　あと１年＞
＜宇宙戦艦ヤマトは　希望を求め→
１６万８０００光年のかなた
イスカンダルに向け　旅立つ＞
＜ガミラスの指導者
デスラー総統は→
歴戦の指揮官　ドメルを
ヤマト討伐のため→
銀河系へと　差し向けるのだった＞
（デスラー）そうか…。→
I see.
やはり　イスカンダル人が
乗っていたのだね。
So the Iscandarians had it.
（セレステラ）はい。
ミレーネルが→
Yes.
Mirenel sacrificed herself to tell me this.
死を賭して　私に。
So you are now the last of the Jirels.
（デスラー）ジレルの一族も
とうとう　君一人か。
（セレステラ）この命は　総統に
救っていただいたもの。→
You saved my life, Your Lordship.
（セレステラ）この命は　総統に
救っていただいたもの。→
たとえ　最後の一人になろうとも→
Even if I am the last, I shall remain loyal to you.
あなたに　忠誠を尽くします。
（デスラー）忠誠か…。
Loyal, huh?
Planet Alteria - Nord Greater Province
（ギムレー）
原住民の反乱一つ　鎮圧できず→
So you ran, unable to deal with a single, native rebellion?
あなたは　逃げ出してきたのね？
（総督）ヤツらは　首都を包囲し→
They surrounded the capital. There was nothing we could do!
手の施しようがなかったのだ。
頼む　ギムレー長官。→
Please, Director-General Gimleh!
この艦隊で　逃げ遅れた移民団の→
Please use this fleet to protect the refugees that couldn't evacuate!
避難と保護を。
（ギムレー）んん～→
Let us burn this planet to the ground.
この星は　焼き尽くしましょう。
えっ!?
（ギムレー）
帝国と総統に　反旗を翻す星は→
A planet that rebels against the Leader and the Empire
must not be allowed to exist in Great Garmillas territory.
大ガミラスの版図に
存在してはなりません。→
総統への忠誠に欠けた
あなたもですよ　総督。
That also goes for you, Governor.
That joke isn't funny...
じょ…　冗談はよせ。　あっ！
ズキュン！（銃声）
（総督）ぐわっ！
I dislike jokes.
（ギムレー）冗談は　嫌いです。
Now, play the melody of destruction!
（ギムレー）
さあ！　殲滅のメロディーを！
（ガミラス国歌）
ドォーーン!!
ピシュン！
ドーン！　ドーン！
ドーン！
Wave Motion Gun Control Room
（整備士）重力アンカーは
こいつの駐退機だからな→
This is the recoil brake for the gravity anchor.
接続確認　怠るなよ。
（整備士）あれ？
Make sure it's fastened securely.
Huh? What are you doing here at this hour?
どうしたの？　こんな時間に。
（百合亜）これは…→
What... What is this?
これは　なんですか？
はい？
Huh?
えっ？
いや　波動砲なんですけど…。
It's the Wave Motion Gun.
（百合亜）あっ…　はてな？
Huh?
（篠原）それって変じゃない？→
Weird, isn't it? Just leave it to the mechanics.
整備に任せとけばいいのに。
（玲）自分の乗る機体は
自分で見ておきたいの。
I want to see the craft I'm piloting for myself.
（篠原）情が深いねぇ。
（玲）ここが　ちょっと…。
You have an attachment to it.
I don't like the way this looks.
≪コツ　コツ　コツ…（足音）
（２人）あっ。
（玲）古代さ…。
Kodai?
- You're still doing that?
- Of course.
（古代進）まだやるつもりかい？
（森雪）もちろん！
今度は　戦闘機だって
乗りこなせるところを→
Next time, I'll show you I can pilot a fighter.
見せてあげる。
銀河系を出たっていうのに
敵との接触が増えてるんだ。
We left the Milky Way, but we're encountering the enemy more often.
- You won't get to?
- I'm being serious.
こいつに乗るなんて…。
真面目に言ってるの。
なので
よろしくお願いします。　あっ。
So please take the time to teach me.
あっ。
（篠原）うわっ！　おっとと…。→
ぐわっ！　痛っ…。
篠原！　あっ。
Ow.
Shinohara!
（篠原）いってぇ…。
彼女　どうかしたのか？
Did something happen with her?
はぁ…
いろいろあるってことですよ。
A lot of things. But I guess you wouldn't know.
って言っても
あんたにゃ分かんないか。
えっ？　なんの話だ？
What is he talking about?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ビィーー！（警報）
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（相原）総員→
All crew to battle stations.
第一種戦闘配備。
またかよ。
Again.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（相原）
繰り返す。　総員　第一種戦闘配備。
Repeat, all crew to battle stations.
配置に着け！
急げ　急げ！
Hurry! Hurry!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）スクランブル。
航空隊　発進準備に入れ。→
Scramble. Fighters, prepare to launch.
カタパルト要員　発艦準備　急げ。→
Catapult crew, prepare for launch.
繰り返す。
カタパルト要員　発艦準備　急げ。
Repeat, catapult crew, prepare for launch.
（西条）敵巡洋艦　２。
代わります。
Two enemy cruisers.
I'll take over.
Thanks.
（西条）お願いします。
また　いつもの威力偵察か？
- More force reconnaissance?
- Ask the enemy.
（島）敵さんに聞いてくれ。
All crew, stand by at battle stations.
（真田）
全艦　第一種戦闘配備のまま待機。
距離９０００。　速度変わらず。
Distance is 9,000. Speed unchanged.
距離８０００。
Distance is now 8,000.
ピッ　ピッ…
あっ。　敵艦　反転！
Enemy's turning around!
（沢村）んんっ！
戦闘準備　戦闘準備って→
They keep calling us to battle stations!
こう出たり入ったりじゃ
身がもたない…。
We'll never get a chance to rest if we?
≪ガン！
（一同）おっ？
（一同）おぉ…。
I guess I can understand her being upset.
（加藤）はぁ～
カリカリするのも　しかたなしか。
ははっ…　いろいろあるんですよ。
She has stuff going on.
（平田）ＯＭＣＳの修理には
まだ時間がかかります。→
It will take time to get the OMCS back on line.
どこかで
水と食料を補給しないと→
We'll need to find food and water, or our stores may run out.
備蓄が
底をつくおそれがあります。
簡単に　補給と言うが→
But there are barely any systems in this area.
この銀河間空間に
恒星系なんて　ほとんど…。
（新見）あるわ。
えっ？
There's one.
The map Iscandar sent us says that a system lies four light years ahead.
（新見）イスカンダルからの
海図には　４光年先に→
恒星系の存在が記されていました。
恒星の名は…。
Its name is Beemela.
ピッピッピッ（操作音）
（新見）ビーメラ。
ビーメラ。
（新見）観測によると→
Beemela...
Observation suggests the system's fourth planet is likely an Earth-type.
この第４惑星が　水と大気がある→
地球型の可能性が高いのよ。
ありがたい。
That's great.
（新見）
地球を抜錨して以来　狭い艦内で→
We've been on this tiny ship for too long.
Many of the crew are suffering from heavy stress.
乗員の多くが
ストレスを抱えています。→
メンタル面でも　上陸は望ましいかと。
（真田）うむ…。
I think it would be good for us to land.
島　航海科としては　どうなんだ？
Navigator Shima, your opinion?
うん　まあ…。
It's fine, I guess.
スケジュールに
支障は　出ないのか？
It won't cause a problem with the schedule?
（島）いや　大丈夫だ。
No, we'll be okay.
そうか。
（伊東）ふっ。
I see.
（小浜）きついよなぁ。→
This is rough.
こんなのが　毎日続いたら
精神的にもたないよ。
I'm gonna go nuts if we keep having to eat this every day.
I don't really feel like I've gotten any sleep.
（崎山）俺　なんか寝た気がしない。
（柏木）ねえ
それより　イスカンダルなんて→
Do you think Iscandar actually exists?
ほんとに　あるのかな？
（薮）やだやだ…。
Jeez...
≪（真琴）ほんとだってば！
ん？
It's true!
（加藤）へえ～…。
（真琴）きれいな女の人の→
Everyone's talking about a pretty girl's ghost that people keep seeing.
幽霊を見たって
うわさになってるんだよ。→
航海科の林さんも見たんだって。
Hayashi, from navigation, saw it.
（加藤）そうなんだ…。
その幽霊っていうのがさ→
Really...
And they say that this ghost may be an alien.
実は宇宙人じゃないかっていう…。
はぁ～ん。
あっ…　んん～？
えっ　なんだよ？
元気ないから熱あるのかな～って。
What?
You look tired, so I was checking if you have a fever.
≪（早乙女）これっぽっちじゃ
体が　もちませんよ！
This isn't enough food.
（平田）ＯＭＣＳが不調なんだ。
今は　これで我慢してくれ。
The OMCS is down.
For now, it'll have to do.
はぁ…　みんな　疲れてるんだよ。
Everyone's tired.
（早乙女）はぁ…。　んんっ！
あぁ～…。
（柏木）食事の質は士気に関わるわ。
（薮）こんなんで→
Food quality directly affects morale.
Are we really gonna be okay?
大丈夫なのかねぇ。
（３人）ん？
（相原）
うっ…　ごほっ　ごほっ　ごほっ！
んん…　はぁ～。
あっ　岬さん。　最近　ラジオの方→
Oh, Misaki!
You haven't been running your radio lately... What's wrong?
やってない…　みたいだけど…
どうしたの？
（百合亜）波動砲の原理は
ブチンスキー波動方程式の→
Is the Wave Motion Gun
based on a specific solution of the Buchinsky Wave Motion formula?
特殊解に基づいているの？
ん!?→
よく調べたね。　特殊解に従い
コンパクト化された→
You've done your homework.
This solution allows us to release part of a miniaturized Calabi-Yau manifold.
カラビ・ヤウ空間の一部を
解放してやるんだ。
（百合亜）
そのときのエネルギー放出量は→
Is the released energy proportional to the space-time super symmetry moduli?
時空超対称性モジュライの
散逸に比例する？
んん～。
いや　超対称性モジュライと→
No, it isn't directly correlated to the super symmetry moduli.
じかに
結び付いているわけではない。→
本質は　超弦コンパクト化の
ランドスケープなんだ。
At its core, it's a miniaturized superstring landscape.
だとすると
超弦真空が発散しないかしら？→
Wouldn't that cause the superstring vacuum to dissipate?
宇宙が　引き裂かれてしまう。
はっ…。
The universe would be torn apart...
≫（星名）百合亜ちゃん！
≫コツ　コツ　コツ…
Yuria... Let's go over there.
（星名）向こう行こうよ。
カシャ（シャッター音）
（太田）へへっ。
ああ～…　くぅ…。
ユークリッド二次元ブラックホールの破綻か。
The collapse of a Euclidean two-dimensional black hole?
うん　気付かなかったな。
I never realized.
（太田）いや～　百合亜ちゃん
髪型変えると　新鮮だな～。
I love Yuria's new hairstyle.
えっ　髪型変わっていたの？
She changed her hair?
（百合亜）
間違いない…　間違いないよ。
I'm certain... I'm sure of it!
（星名）えっ？
波動砲は…→
The Wave Motion Gun... That weapon of mass destruction.
あの大量破壊兵器は
あの人が作ったの。
He must have made it.
The Leader is coming here, to Balun, for an inspection?
（ゲール）
総統が　視察にいらっしゃる？→
このバランにですか？
（ドメル）ディッツ提督の話では→
Admiral Ditz says that he's coming in secret.
どうやら　お忍びらしい。
（ゲール）では早速　お出迎えの準備を。
Then we should prepare a reception!
If we wish to demonstrate our loyalty, we must first defeat the Yamato.
（ハイデルン）
総統への忠誠を　示されたいなら→
まず　ヤマトを討つことです。
（ゲットー）こちらの威力偵察で→
Our force recon has probably exhausted them.
神経も　すり減ってる頃だ。
Then it's time to strike!
（バーガー）たたく頃合いだよな。
（クライツェ）偵察大隊の報告では→
Our recon battalion says that the Yamato has set course for the Beemela system.
ヤマトは
ビーメラ星系に転針したとか。
That's right.
（ドメル）そうだ。　そして
ビーメラとヤマトの間には→
And this neutron star, Carell 163, lies between them and Beemela.
この中性子星
カレル１６３がある。→
ヤツが　ジャンプすれば
カレル１６３の→
If they jump, Carell 163's gravity well will interfere,
重力勾配が影響して　ずれが生じ→
causing them to Geschtam out at one of these five points.
この５つのポイントいずれかに→
ゲシュタムアウトするはずだ。
我々は　その隙をつく。
We will attack then.
この５か所に　艦隊を配し→
Deploy fleets at these five locations, and as soon as you see the Yamato, gather...
ヤマトを発見ししだい
各部隊は　直ちに集結。→
全力で　これをたたく！
...and destroy them.
（ゲットー　バーガー　クライツェ　ハイデルン）
ザー・ベルク！
Zar Belk!
（ゲール）えっ？　えっ？
サァーー（雨音）
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウィン　ウィン　ウィン…（サイレン）
はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…→
うっ…。　くっ！
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（警官）
止まれ！　逃げても無駄だ！
Stop! Running is useless.
（警官・通信）
反乱分子を　人間だと思うな。→
Don't even think of the rebels as people. They are fleas.
ヤツらは　ダニだ。→
If they resist, kill them.
抵抗した場合は　射殺せよ。
はぁ　はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
≫ガチャ（車のドアの音）
（秘密警察）
ここだ。　確かに　逃げ込んだ。
This is the place.
I saw them run in here.
（秘密警察）突入準備。
（秘密警察）おい→
Prepare to enter.
This house is...
この家は…。
Domel
All ships are ready to launch.
（兵士）
全艦　発進準備　完了しました。
全艦　発進！
All ships, launch!
Joint Staff Operations, Division 9.
（新見）
幕僚監部作戦部　９課所属。→
先生たちが
ヤマト計画を　立案した部署ね。
That was where they proposed the Yamato Plan.
９８年９月７日　同課に配属。→
Joined the department on September 7th, '98.
Admiral Hijikata recommended her for the position.
推薦したのは　土方宙将。
（伊東）土方？
Hijikata?
１年ほど前から　死別した両親の
友人であった土方宙将が→
For the past year, since her parents died, Hijikata has been her guardian.
彼女の後見人になってるわ。
（伊東）１年前…。
兄弟はなし。
One year?
No siblings.
父親は　外務次官　森直之。
（伊東）土方か。→
Her father was Undersecretary for Foreign Affairs, Naoyuki Mori.
Hijikata?
あの男なら　やりかねない。
えっ？
I can easily imagine him doing it...
（伊東）経歴改ざんですよ。
（新見）まさか…。
Altering her records.
You aren't serious.
I am serious.
その　まさかです。
Professional intuition?
プロの勘？
（伊東）そんなところですね。
Something like that.
なんで　彼女に興味を？
気があるとか？
Why so interested in her?
Got a crush?
You don't need to know why.
（伊東）知らなくていいことです。
次の目的地　ここは有力よ。
Our next stop looks quite promising.
Then we'll be busy.
（伊東）
それはそれは　忙しくなりそうだ。
老婆心ながら
副長には関わらない方がいいかと。
Just a word of advice... Stay away from the XO.
んん…。
（伊東）そうは言っても→
But even so, I'd like some insurance.
保険は　欲しいところか。
Leave it to me. I know where to go.
（新見）任せて。　当てがあるの。
≫シューン（ドアの音）
Hayashi? I've got that data input...
（島）林か？　データの入力は
もう済ませ…　ん？
I brought you this.
差し入れ。
ありがとう。
Thanks.
ふぅ～。　どう？　日程の方は。
How's the schedule looking?
スケジュールどおりにいってる？
Are we on track?
We'll be fine. We're making good progress.
まっ　大丈夫。　順調さ。
ふふっ。
ん？
うそが下手ね。
えっ？
You're a terrible liar.
私　カウンセラーよ。
I'm a counselor.
This voyage's success depends on you.
この航海の成否は
あなたに懸かっている。
You're the most important person on this ship.
あなたが　この艦の要なんだわ。
Navigation Officer...
（星名）航海長。
ん？
お時間　頂けますか？
May I have a moment?
Linking with system satellites. Opening Geschtam Gates to Balun.
（航宙士）システム衛星とリンク。
バランへのゲシュタムの門→
開きます。
ゲート開門まで　あと２０ゲック。
Twenty gek until Gate opens.
（艦長）総統　本艦は　間もなく
ゲシュタムの門に入ります。→
Leader, our ship is now entering the Geschtam Gate.
これを抜けますと　バランです。
Balun lies just beyond.
（航宙士）
メインエンジンに　異常発生！
Problem in main engine.
内圧が上昇中！　このままでは
オーバーブーストします。
Pressure is rising. At this rate, it will over-boost!
安定させろ！　早く！
Stabilize it! Now!
ドォーン！
ドドォーーン!!
ドン！
（ゼーリック）総統が不在とは→
The Leader is missing?
どういうわけであるか!?
そして　ディッツ君→
Why?
And you, Ditz!
なぜ　君だけが　その事実を→
Why are you the only one who knew this?
知っていたのであるのか!?
（タラン）総統の気まぐれは
いつものことだよ。
The Leader's whims are nothing new.
（ギムレー）元帥閣下は　いろいろと
ご不満が　おありなのですよ。
The marshal seems dissatisfied.
（ゼーリック）オルタリア蜂起を鎮圧し→
You're rather pleased, after putting down the rebellion on Alteria.
貴公は　意気軒昂であるな。
I did not put it down. I annihilated the planet.
（ギムレー）
鎮圧ではありません。　殲滅です。
The Imperial Guard goes too far.
（ガデル）
親衛隊は　やり過ぎだ！
That isn't true.
（セレステラ）それは違います。→
恐怖なくしては
帝国内の結束は保てません。
We cannot maintain peace in the Empire without fear.
ふっ。
ヤマト出現以来　各惑星管区で→
It's true that rebellions have cropped up everywhere since the Yamato appeared.
蜂起が続いているのは事実だ。
だが　これでは　かえって…。
But this just makes it worse...
純血こそ正義！
Pure bloods are the only ones who matter.
We cannot trust the barbarians who do not have blue skin.
やはり　青い肌を持たぬ異民族は→
信用できぬということであるよ。
≪シューン
ん？
Men, this is no time for talk!
（ヒス）諸君！　悠長に
閣議などしてる場合ではないぞ。→
The Leader's Deusura has exploded.
総統のデウスーラが
爆破された！→
Lord Desler has been assassinated!
デスラー総統が　暗殺されたのだ！
Message from scout ship. They have sighted the Yamato.
（通信士）斥候艦より入電
「我　ヤマトを捕捉」。
Have the scouts provoke the Yamato. Force them into jumping.
斥候艦に　ヤマトを挑発させろ。
ヤツを　ジャンプさせるんだ。
（太田）ワープ針路上
障害物　認められない。
No obstacles in our warp path.
中性子星の影響は？
Effects from the neutron star?
航路が　ゆがめられているのは
確かですね。
Our course will be affected.
全艦　ワープ準備。
All crew, prepare for warp.
ピーン（レーダーの音）
あっ　レーダーに感。
Ship on our radar. Two enemy ships.
敵艦　２　後方より近づく。
敵速　７エスノット。
Approaching from our rear. Enemy speed is seven s-knots.
（南部）はぁ…
また　いつもの威力偵察だろ。
More force recon, right?
ピシュー！　ピシュー！
ドォーン！
（一同）うわっ！
Damage to our port side.
左舷に被弾！
（南部）応戦しましょう！
Let's strike back.
（真田）いや　このまま　ワープする。
（南部）しかし…。
No, go to warp.
But...
補給も　ままならない現在
無駄な戦闘に→
Without sufficient supplies, it would be folly to engage.
時間を取られるべきではない。
（島）副長！
XO, the neutron star will affect our warp.
中性子星団の影響で
航路が　かなり　ゆがめられます。
Try to compensate, then go to warp!
補正計算を行い　直ちにワープ。
（真田）状況報告。
Report!
（太田）１０時の方向に　中性子星。
Neutron star is at ten o'clock.
So it did affect us.
（真田）やはり　影響を受けたか。
ビー　ビー（警告音）
あっ　レーダーに感。
Ships on our radar.
艦首前方　敵艦隊。
Enemy fleet off our bow.
後方からも接近！
Our rear, as well!
Multiple ships surrounding us!
艦影　多数。　囲まれます！
（ゲール）
ヤマトめ　ここに出てきたか。→
So that's where the Yamato ended up emerging!
飛んで火に入る夏の虫だ！
Right into our trap!
Order all ships to rendezvous.
各隊に通達。　直ちに集結。
航空隊　発進せよ。
≫（沖田十三）待て。
Launch fighters.
Wait.
ハヤブサを展開する時間はない。
No time to launch the Hayabusas.
They would be hit while trying.
敵は　その隙をつき　仕掛けてくる。
艦長！
Captain!
波動防壁　艦首へ最大展開。
Deploy Wave Motion Shield at maximum.
第２戦速で　敵正面に突入。
Charge them at combat speed 2. We'll break through!
これを突破する！
（真田）はっ！
Yes, sir.
But...
しかし　前方には
旗艦と思われる　超弩級戦艦が。
There's a Super-Dreadnought class ship in front of us!
死中に活を見いださねば→
We'll never make it through without taking risks!
この包囲を破ることはできない！
ピシュー　ピシュー　ピシュー…
ババババッ！
ドカン　ドカン　ドカン　ドカン…
Attack on our keel's shield.
（南部）艦艇防壁に被弾！
艦首魚雷発射管　開け。
Open torpedo tubes on bow!
（太田）
波動防壁　避弾経始圧　低下。→
Wave Motion Shield's deflection ability is decreasing.
If we keep taking hits, they'll penetrate it!
このまま　直撃を受け続けると
貫通されます。
We'll strike their center. Concentrate fire to our front.
敵艦隊の芯をつく。
火力を　前方に集中。
撃ち方　始めぇ！
Open fire!
ビシュン！　ビシュン！
バシュー　バシュー　バシュー！
ドォーン！
ガン！
1604 has been hit.
（兵士）１６０４　被弾！
後方に下がらせ　後続艦と交代。
Have them withdraw and switch position with the ship behind.
ピシュー　ピシュー　ピシュー…
バシュー　バシュー　バシュー！
ビシュン！　ビシュン！
ビシュン！
ドォーン！
ダダダダッ！
ドォーン！　ドォーン！
ビシュン！
ガン！
Wave Motion Shield is at critical point. Shield is dissipating!
波動防壁　臨界点！　防壁消失！
The Yamato has broken through our front ships. It's approaching.
ヤマト
前衛艦隊を突破。　接近します。
The Yamato is a fierce opponent.
ヤマト　侮りがたし。
ドメル司令…。
Commander Domel!
Open all gunports! Destroy the Yamato!
全砲門　開け。　ヤマトをしとめる！
ピシュー　ピシュー　ピシュー！
ドォーン！
くっそ～！
Damn it!
≪ドォーン！
（一同）うわぁ～！
Engine Room! What's wrong?
（徳川）機関室どうした!?
第一砲塔　沈黙！
Gunport 1 is down!
Radar is gone.
レーダー　大破！
慣性航法に切り替え。
Switch to inertial navigation!
足を止めるな！
Don't slow down!
狙うは旗艦　ただ一隻！
We're only after one ship.
Keep going, and ram it if you must.
ぶつける覚悟で進め！
は…　はい！
Right... Got it!
ビシュン！
カン！
ぐっ！
ピシュー！
か…　回避～！
退くな！→
Evasive maneuvers!
Hold position! The Domelaze does not retreat!
ドメラーズは　一歩も退かん！
撃てぇ～！
Fire!
ビシュン！
ドォーン！
機関全開！　このまま振り切る！
Engines to full!
Shake them off!
Battle stations!
戦闘配置！
（バーガー）いたいた～！
獲物だぜ　おやじさん！
There it is!
There's our prey!
（ハイデルン・通信）
はしゃぐな　バーガー！
Stay quiet, fool.
Second squad is in position.
別動隊　配置に着きます。
This is checkmate.
これで　チェックメイトだ。
ピシュー　ピシュー　ピシュー…
ババババッ…
ドォーン！
ビシュン！
Flying Squadron 3, strike from right side.
（ドメル）
第３遊撃戦隊　右翼からたたけ。
ドメル司令　本国から通信です。
Commander Domel, a message from the home planet.
Later.
後にしろ。
（ゲール）総統府からの→
It's a class-one priority message from the Leader's Office.
第１級優先通信です。
総統府から？
The Leader's Office?
ビシュン！　ビシュン！
ドォーン！
ドォーーン!!
第二副砲　どうした!?　返事しろ！
Secondary gunport 2, what's wrong'?
Come in!
（２人）うわっ！
（太田）右舷直撃　２！
Engine output is dropping!
Secondary gunport 2, are you there?
うっ！
両舷魚雷　何やってる!?　弾幕　張れ。
Torpedoes! What are you doing? Lay down some fire!
（ドメル）帰投命令？
An order to return home?
Why, Deputy Lord Hyss?
なぜです!?　ヒス副総統！
私は　あと一歩で　ヤマトに…。
I almost have the Yamato...
No questions.
（通信）質問は　許されない。→
Withdraw the fleet, and return to the home planet.
今すぐ　艦隊を撤収し
本国に帰還せよ。→
これは最優先命令だ。　分かったな？
This is a top-priority order. Understood?
（ドメル）んん～…。
ドォーーン!!
第三砲塔　撃ち続けろ！
（島）舵が利かない！
Gunport 3, keep firing!
くっ！
くそ…　ここで沈むのかよ!?
Damn it! Are we going to die here?
バカ野郎！　諦めるな！
Don't be stupid!
Don't give up!
ん？
なんだ？
What?
（ＡＵ０９）
敵艦　ワープ　シテイキマス。
Enemy ships are warping out.
（ＡＵ０９）
敵艦隊　全艦　ワープ　シマシタ。
All enemy ships have warped out.
どういうこと？
What's going on?
They were this close... Why?
ここまで追い込んでおいて
なぜだ？
（心の声）≪敵に　何かがあった≫
Something happened over there.
But what?
≪だが一体　何が？≫
Episode 15: Point of No Return
The Yamato weighs anchor and rests its wounded body,
upon an Earth-like planet.
This is a place longed-for by those who will soon be extinct.
A conspiracy raises its head,
and we are asked what path we should take.
Next time: A Choice for the Future.
There are 287 days left before humanity is extinct.
広島県呉市の山に
同級生だった女性の遺体を捨てた
として、
１６歳の少女が逮捕された事件で
警察は、第三者が関与した可能性
もあると見て捜査している。